<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Thomas Tiveron</title>
    <link>http://tiveron.ca/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Thomas Tiveron</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>thomas@tiveron.ca (Thomas Tiveron)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>thomas@tiveron.ca (Thomas Tiveron)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://tiveron.ca/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I Learn Julia?</title>
      <link>http://tiveron.ca/blog/should-i-learn-julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>thomas@tiveron.ca (Thomas Tiveron)</author>
      <guid>http://tiveron.ca/blog/should-i-learn-julia/</guid>
      <description>Why Julia, Why Now? Programming is a diverse field! You have people from all around the world, tackling every sort of problem imaginable with their computers. From web-developers, to mobile app creators, from legacy code maintainers, to scientific computing mathematicians, many people need different features and different languages.
Julia  is a relatively young language, released in 2012, and was designed to meet the high-performance needs of numerical and scientific programming; while being a general-purpose programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I Learn R or Python?</title>
      <link>http://tiveron.ca/blog/learning-r-or-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 21:16:38 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>thomas@tiveron.ca (Thomas Tiveron)</author>
      <guid>http://tiveron.ca/blog/learning-r-or-python/</guid>
      <description>R or Python for Data Science So you want to be a data scientist, but are stuck on the first polarizing decision of learning R or Python&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to help you!
I&amp;rsquo;m also going to attempt to not make this post follow the typical &amp;ldquo;R is maybe the best, or Python, or neither&amp;rdquo;, as I find these kind of articles informative, but not that helpful. If you are wanting a break down of R and Python&amp;rsquo;s strengths, ease of learning, salaries, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>