<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Thomas Tiveron</title>
    <link>http://tiveron.ca/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Thomas Tiveron</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>thomas@tiveron.ca (Thomas Tiveron)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>thomas@tiveron.ca (Thomas Tiveron)</webMaster>
    <atom:link href="http://tiveron.ca/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi, I&#39;m Thomas</title>
      <link>http://tiveron.ca/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>thomas@tiveron.ca (Thomas Tiveron)</author>
      <guid>http://tiveron.ca/page/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to focus on backend solutions where I can flex my mathematical muscle :p &lt;br&gt;
  I&amp;rsquo;m blogging to share my journey on learning to become a better software developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;longer-version&#34;&gt;Longer version,&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently working remotely with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icarusgv.com/&#34; target=&#34;\_blank&#34;&gt; Icarus Group Ventures, &lt;/a&gt; a small FinTech start-up.
  I was initially solely in the role of manager; planning, scheduling, hiring,
  but when you work on a small team you get the chance to tackle many different challenges. Over the past few years,
  I have been able to add value through helping out with development, and system administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past couple years I have worked with either small start-ups, or on small teams contracted by large companies to solve a specific problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the start-up realm, I&amp;rsquo;ve helped get multiple ideas funded and a couple to market. Helping people get from an idea to a workable plan can be a big challenge,
  but the results are often rewarding. The start-ups I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with have been under 5 members and are mostly in need of planning and prototyping.
  A lot of the work at this stage is idea validation, which means figuring out if there is a genuine need, and if it can be profitable (or sustainable).
  Getting good answers here can solve a lot of heartache and hard work. In fact over half the start-ups I&amp;rsquo;ve helped with their research have decided against
  pursuing funding, but this is just what you want at an early stage - Fail Fast! Learn the lessons, and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my work on contract teams, I&amp;rsquo;m usually solving a company/industry specific problem with a tight schedule and fixed budget. My background in civil engineering
  usually comes into play here, where I look to bring a digital solution to an analog problem. Sometimes, there are fulltime developers, and I take on a liaison role filtering key
  engineering concepts into pseudocode or ensuring the logic adequately reflects real world processes. Other times, I&amp;rsquo;m the developer and often in this scenario a key
  factor is integration. Fitting a new application or process into a company&amp;rsquo;s current work flow and culture can be tricky. Early communication between stakeholders &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; end-users is key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Ryerson University (Toronto, Ontario, Canada) and completed a Bachelor of Civil Engineering, followed by a Masters of Applied Science there too.
  It was during my master&amp;rsquo;s thesis that I was first introduced to programming, translating some old VB6 code to VB.Net and Silverlight.
  Since then I have tackled numerous small coding projects. I have done some work in Python (2 &amp;amp; 3), a little more in R, and a little less on the front-end (HTML &amp;amp; CSS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julia is currently my crush, don&amp;rsquo;t tell my wife&amp;hellip; Blogs about JuliaLang to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve made it this far thank you,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>